Hello friends welcome to my new YouTube
channel policy
plus today we are going to see the video
best health insurance policy
2024 before going to video I request you
all if you want health insurance please
call in WhatsApp 934
9036 in this video we are going to
compare following
plans star smart Health Pro aiaa active
one care Supreme htfc Optima secure n
buba as per gold plan that is low
variant plan Tata Medicare Premier
plan manipal Prime
product IC Lumbard Health Advantage
eligibility age
limit year smart Health Pro allowing
entry age up to 50 only other most of
the plans allowing entry age up to 65
normally active one and cash Supreme up
to any age allowing so any person can
enter any
availability some insure
range here smart BR allowing up to one
CR other important planets like tataa
Medicare Premier and ICA Lumbard
allowing up to 3 core
suure room rent limit this is Main
future we have to consider before taking
any health insurance because it will
affect the overall claim
bill here smart Health
Pro and manipal Prime IC Lumbard giving
uh single private room or single AC room
but they have option uh higher sumers
shot for example 10 L or 20 L they are
giving any room
category other plans care Supreme naaba
HDFC Tata Premier active one giving any
room category
default before continue the video I
request all if you not subscribe this
Channel Please Subscribe the channel
also click this Bell button uh
for future video notification
threee and post
hospital here most of the plant giving
60 days and 180
days some
plans data Medicare giving 60 and 90
days and
uh 75 LHS above polic only giving 200
days
no claim
bonus here most of the plan
giving 50% bonus on some plans uh say
example anaa giving 100 100% uh that is
booster plus like this active one also
giving 100% and some plants giving
optional a bonus so which one you want
consider that
plan and a restore
option here also most of the plan giving
one time uh some plans for example smart
Pro Care active
one giving unter present and unlimited
times
tataa Medicare only giving uh 100% only
that also 45 days uh delay between uh
one claim to another other plans no
issues share accommodation if you stay
in share accommodation health insurance
give some
benefit some plans say example small Pro
or care Supreme they are giving policy
time if you take uh share accommodation
you will get premium
discount some plans say example HDFC or
tataa Medicare Moneyball Prime they are
giving after claim time if you take uh
share accommodation you will get uh cash
discount or cash wallet whatever so you
will get some uh amount per day how many
days you staying that time you will get
some money for uh
discount pre-existing disses say example
uh pressure sugar um we have to consider
that as a pre-existing dises uh that
will apply waiting
period here most of the plant they are
giving uh 3 years or 4 years but they
are giving option to reduce up to uh one
year or instant cover also for example
car Supreme activ one they are giving
instant cover n also they are giving uh
instant
cover specific dises uh say example
specific surgery kidney stone Hera joint
replacement uh like this operations
waiting period apply for uh even if you
have dishes or not all person have to
pass this waiting
period most of the plans comes with 2
years waiting period at1 and Care have
the option to reduce to one year even n
also have the option to reduce up to one
year maternity
cover this features mostly uh more
people not requested because um
Maternity in lifetime one or two times
only we have to consider so for that you
have to consider the plan or not that is
your choice some plans for example uh
neaa or Tata I Lumbard pipal they are
giving uh delivery coverage also up to
sudden
limit bartic surgery weight loss surgery
here some plans active one moneyall and
IC lard they
are giving up to sumers shot limit tataa
Premier they are also giving up to
sumers shot but reasonable amount only
we have to claim other plant smart
Health Pro are care Nea bua and HDFC no
cover kro serger limit some plans they
will put the limit for cat surgery so we
have to consider this feature
also here most of the plant comes with
no conditions that means we have the
option to claim up to actual
amount Health checkup uh today we are
going to take policy means this year no
claim means next renewal time we have
the option to
uh take Health checkup at free of cost
so that feature also we have to
consider here most of the plants giving
option in amount wise or test wise uh
they are giving some plants uh say
example active one they are giving
optional care also they are giving as a
optional ambulance cover
here most of the plan giving actual
amount care and ICC Lumbard data have
some conditions that means some
limitations in life threatening issues
we have option to use air ambulance
also smart Health Pro
giving 10% of Summer should has a limit
care giving 5 lakhs htfc other plans
also giving 5 lakhs but n and ICC money
giving maximum up to Summer suit or 10
lak like this they are giving AC one
have no
options I treatment
s like that treatment coverage limit
here most of the plants have no limit so
we have the option to claim up to
Summers shoot are
actual Argan donor
expenses smart Health Pro have no
options that means if you take Argan
from someone uh that amount we have to
PIR only
we have no option in smart Health
Pro advaned treatment that is modern
treatment like robotic surgery or
chemotherapy for cancer like this
treatment here most of the plants uh
comes with actual claim so no limitation
only manipol Prime have 5 laks policy
meant 50% other option means no
issues domicillary Hospital in emergency
conditions Hospital have no bed or uh
patient conditions not eligible are not
good to take up to hospital in this
condition domiciliary hospit cover is
possible
here most of the plan giving up to
Summer should as a
limit Home Care treatment in some cases
we can take a treatment in home also
eligible to
claim this feature smart Pro have also
NAA data Medicare and ICC Lumbard active
one have the option also htfc also have
the option some plan giving limitation
some plans giving
actual coverage for non-medical items
this is the main feature we have to
consider before health insurance because
uh this is the cost like gloves mask
sanitizer uh cost will come 20% of the
surgery
so if your plan not have this option
means we have to pay the uh 20% of
amount from our own
pocket here most of the plant coming
with a default or optional Rider so no
issues extra
benefit smart Health option to uh reduce
the premium up to 20% in Renewal by T
wellness
program have to own option up to uh
Health returns are a wellness program
and reduce the premium up to
100% HIV HS STD cover and mental illness
cover they are providing and P claim
deductable option so we have the reduce
the premium by uh sudden limitation
after only coverage like this if you
have to take we will get the premium
discount and prefer network provider
discount cancer booster and a compensate
visit a durable equipment cover like the
extra benefit available in AC
one care Supreme also wellness program
20%
sorry 30%
discount
htfc they are giving dental treatment
and a deductible option
NBA they are
giving lock the clock and wellness
program fast forward option so 3E
coverage we have the option to take in
one year uh Future Ready
options uh if you take Plan uh future if
you add your wife uh without uh waiting
Trad possible to add and a borderless
that means Global cover and cash back
every claim pre year you will get uh
some extra uh cash back offer and
deductable
option here lock the feature they are
giving but in future they have um change
the policy also like this they
mentioned da Medicare Premier if you
stay in the
hospital more than uh 10 days means you
will get uh 1 percentage of Sumer
sh and I and
diagnos coverage and OPD coverage OPD
Dental exal cover like this benefit they
are
giving moneyall Prime product they are
giving switch off option if you take
policy and went for foreign means you
can off the coverage for uh some days or
some month so you will get some premium
discount and the wellness program prefer
Network Hospital discount premium waiver
and HIV AIDS mental illness cover they
are
providing ICC lumbar they are giving
animal pite EXN cover worldwide cover
nursing at home
Futures nursing at home future means
after uh discharge of any s
surgery or 10 days or some days uh we
have used the nursing uh facility at
home and claim per day 2,000 like this
they are provide and critical illness
and acal
cover and be fit like this future they
are giving as a optional and a
continuous stay for 10 days means we
have option to claim up to 20,000 and Su
sh
productor then Sate mother complication
up to 5 lakhs limit like this feature
they are giving
and premium comparison for husband wife
age up to 35 and two child 5 lak suers
suit here most of the
plants
17,000 and 16,000 they are giving uh
based on the future they are charging
the premium more or
less please share your suggestion and
feedback in comment section if you like
this video please click like button and
subscribe the channel and share to your
friends for health insurance please call
93 493 on WhatsApp I'll see you in next
Insurance video thank you